articleblast.com 2014-03-29

# Crowdtilt Open

Last updated: March 13, 2014 

## 1\. Summary of Services

Crowdtilt Open is a professional and customizable reward-based crowdfunding and e-commerce software and communication service (the "Service"). The Service is hosted by Crowdtilt Open, but may be accessed at one of our customer's domain addresses. 

Crowdtilt Open is a website and service of Crowdtilt, Inc. or its subsidiaries ("Crowdtilt," "Crowdtilt Open,"" "we," "ours" or "us.") Please read this Privacy Policy (the "Privacy Policy") and make sure you understand it. 

This Privacy Policy describes how Crowdtilt Open collects, uses, stores, shares and protects your information in connection with the Service, whether accessible via Crowdtilt Open's domain name or one of our customer's own domain names, co-branded websites (including sub-domains, international versions, and application versions) or our other services, applications, widgets and content provided through or in connection with the Service (collectively, the "Services"). 

## 2\. Application of Privacy Policy

### 2.1. Overview

This Privacy Policy applies when you access, visit or use the Service or a website using the Service and is part of, and is governed by, the terms and conditions set forth in the Crowdtilt Open Terms of Use and Checkout Terms. 

By creating a Crowdtilt Open account, or by otherwise accessing, visiting, using, or transacting through the Service, you expressly consent to our collection, use, disclosure and retention of your information as described in this Privacy Policy and in the Crowdtilt Open's Terms of Use and Checkout Terms, which ever is applicable. 

### 2.2. Modifications

We will notify you of changes to this Privacy Policy by posting the amended Privacy Policy on Open.Crowdtilt.com at least 30 calendar days before the effective date of the changes. If you have provided us with your email address we will also notify you of material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending an email at least 30 calendar days before the effective date of the changes to the email address you most recently provided to us. We encourage you to keep the email address you provide to us current, and to promptly notify us of any changes to your email address, so that you may receive any notices we send to you regarding material changes to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the new Privacy Policy, you may terminate your account within the applicable 30 calendar day period by contacting us or by deleting your account through the account settings link on your profile page, and you will not be bound by the amendments. Otherwise, the new Privacy Policy will take effect after 30 calendar days. 

## 3\. Information Collection Practices

  * _Information You Provide to Us_. We may collect information that you provide to us in connection with your use of the Services when you (i) register as a user of the Service; (ii) make changes to your user profile information, (iii) send e-mail messages, forms, or other information to us through the Service, or (iv) use the Services, such as make a transaction through the Services. If you register for a Crowdtilt Open account directly through the Service, you will be required to provide your email address and create a password. You may also have to provide additional information in connection with your Crowdtilt Open account, including your full name, birthday, your city, state and country of residence, your zip code, and social security number. To collect money being held for you by the Service, you will need to provide payout information, including you bank account information, and compliance and fraud prevention related information. 
  * _Information Automatically Collected Through the Service_. Crowdtilt Open, along with our third party service partners, vendors and business partners may automatically collect information about usage of your Crowdtilt Open site and those who visit and transact through it. The information automatically collected about those accessing or using your Crowdtilt Open site may include, but is not limited to, device ID, device type, browser type and version, geo-location information, computer and connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the Service, ad data, IP address and standard web log information. 
  * Some or our third party service partners, vendors and business partners allow your users to opt-out from the automatic collection of your information. 
    *   To opt-out from having Google Analytics collect and use your information, please visit https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
    *   To opt-out from having ClickTale collect and use your information, please visit http://www.clicktale.net/disable.html.
  * _Cookies and Web Beacons_. Crowdtilt Open, along with our third party service partners, vendors and business partners may use cookies, locally stored objects and web beacons to automatically collect information about your use of the Services. Cookies are small bits of information that are transferred to and stored in separate files within your computer's browser. The Services uses both "persistent cookies" which remain on your computer after you have closed your browser as well as "session cookies" which exist only during a visitor's online session and disappear from your computer when you close your browser. Locally stored objects or "flash cookies" are data files that can be created on your computer by the websites you visit and are a way for websites to store information for later use. Locally stored objects are different than cookies because they are stored in different parts of your computer than cookies. Web beacons are small strings of code that provide a method for delivering a graphic image on a web page or in an email message for the purpose of transferring data. You can set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie. You can also disable the storage of flash cookies. For additional information about managing and disabling flash cookies, please visit http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html. However, if you reject cookies or disable flash cookies you may not be able to use all portions or all functionality of the Services. 

## 4\. Use of Information

Crowdtilt Open may use information that we collect about you through the Services to:

  * Provide access to the Service and to provide you with requested Services and customer support and to process and respond to your inquiries;
  * Personalize, customize, measure, and improve our services, content, and advertising and otherwise to enhance your experience of the Services;
  * Facilitate financial transactions; 
  * Prevent, detect, and investigate potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce the Crowdtilt Open Terms of Use and Checkout Terms;
  * Analyze the accuracy, effectiveness, usability, or popularity of the Service;
  * Generate and review reports and data about our user base and service usage patterns;
  * Compile aggregate data for internal and external business purposes;
  * Resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems;
  * Contact you with information, including promotional, marketing and advertising information and recommendations that we believe may be of interest to you;
  * Provide you with other services requested by you as described when we collect the information; and
  * As otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy or the Crowdtilt Open Terms of Use.

We may also retain your information to so that we may feature your Campaigns or Contributions in association with you and your image on Crowdtilt's various services and in marketing and promotional materials. This right persists even after the close of a Campaign, the termination of these Terms, or after you delete your Member Content. 

## 5\. Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

Crowdtilt Open may disclose your information to the following third parties:

  * _Our Service Providers_. We may share your information with third party contractors or service providers who provide certain services to us or on our behalf, such as operating and supporting the Service, processing payments and payouts, fulfilling orders you place through the Service or otherwise responding to your customer service requests. These service providers will only have access to the information needed to perform these limited functions on our behalf and are required to provide your information with at least the same level of protection and security as we use for the Service. 
  * _Companies that Acquire Our Business or Assets_. If Crowdtilt Open becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, Crowdtilt Open may share or transfer your information to a third party or parties in connection with the applicable transaction. 
  * _Our Affiliates_. We may share some or all of your information with our parent company, subsidiaries and corporate affiliates, joint venturers, or other companies under common control with us. We will require these entities to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy with regard to their use of your information. 
  * _Payment Processor_. To facilitate your financial transactions, we will share financial information, and compliance and fraud related information, with our Payment Processor. At this time our Payment Processor is Balanced Payments. 
  * _Compliance and Fraud_. We may share your personal and financial information with third party companies that assist with our compliance and anti-fraud efforts 
  * _Payment Card Companies_. If you place an order through the Service, the information you provide will be transmitted to your credit card company to verify and authorize your purchase. 
  * _Bank Account Companies_. If you seek a payout through the Service, the information you provide will be transmitted to a payment processor and relevant financial institutions. 
  * _Aggregate Information_. Crowdtilt Open may share information relating to visitors and users of the Service with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties on an aggregate basis. We note that, while this information will not identify your users personally, in some instances these third parties may be able to combine this information with other data they have about you, or that they receive from third parties, in a manner that allows them to identify you personally. 
  * _Law Enforcement Authorities_. To the extent permitted by law, we may share your information with law enforcement, governmental agencies, or authorized third-parties, in response to a verified request relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other Crowdtilt Open user to legal liability, or to protect our rights or property, or during emergencies when safety is at risk. 
  * _DMCA Notices_. We may share your information with third parties when we forward Digital Millennium Copyright Act ("DMCA") infringement notifications and counter-notifications as described in the Terms of Use. DMCA infringement notifications and counter-notifications (including any personal information included as part of the notifications) will be forwarded as submitted to us without any deletions. 

## 6\. Security

Crowdtilt Open is built on top of our public API. Our Public API was audited by a third party and met the most stringent credit card security standards: PCI Compliance Level 1. 

Crowdtilt Open takes reasonable measures to protect the information you provide to Crowdtilt Open or submit through the Service against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification. However, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to Crowdtilt Open or submit through the Service and you do so at your own risk. No internet or email transmission is ever fully secure or error-free. Email sent to or through the Service may not be secure. You should use caution whenever submitting information online and take special care in deciding what information you send to us via email. Say to yourself, "Would I want the NSA to see this?"" 

## 7\. Accessing, Changing and Managing Your Information

You may change and update the information you provide through the Service, or change your preferences concerning how we use your information, as follows: 

  * _Changing or Updating Your Information_. You may make changes to the information you have provided in connection with your Crowdtilt Open account by logging in to your account and changing the applicable information or by contacting us at Open@Crowdtilt.com If you choose to terminate your account, you may also request that we delete your information by contacting us at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com. Following receipt of a request from you, we will take reasonable steps to update, correct or delete your information according the this Privacy Policy. 
  * _Privacy Settings_. If you have concerns about privacy settings, please contact Privacy@Crowdtilt.com. 
  * _Email Communications_. You can make changes regarding receiving email communications from us within your Crowdtilt Open account. You can also choose not to receive email communications from us by following the "unsubscribe" instructions in any email communication you receive from us. 
  * _Social Media Services_. Crowdtilt Open does not control the information you provide through social media services, such as Facebook or Twitter. If you want to change your preferences with regard to how an applicable social media service collects or uses your information in connection with the Services, you should review the privacy practices of the applicable social media service and adjust your privacy or other settings directly through them. 

## 8\. Third Parties

The Service may contain links to websites that are not owned or operated by Crowdtilt Open. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these websites. If you visit these websites or provide any information directly to parties other than Crowdtilt Open (even if those websites display the Crowdtilt Open brand), different policies may apply to the collection and use of your information. We encourage you to investigate and ask questions before accessing third party websites or disclosing information to third parties. 

## 9\. No Children under 13

Crowdtilt Open is not intended for use by children under the age of 13. We will never knowingly collect information directly from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide us with information of any kind whatsoever. If we become aware that a user is under the age of thirteen 13, we will remove his or her information from our files. If you have reason to believe that we may have accidentally received personal information from a child under age 13, please contact us immediately at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com. 

## 10\. Information Processed in the United States

The Service is intended for users located in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States and choose to use the Service or provide your information to us, your information will be transferred, processed and stored in the United States. U.S. privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. Your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of information in connection with the Service represents your agreement to this practice. If you do not want your information transferred to or processed or stored in the United States, you should not use the Service. Use of the Service by users outside of the United States is not authorized by Crowdtilt Open and is at your own risk. 

## 11\. Retention of Your Information

We retain information for active Crowdtilt Open accounts as long as it is necessary and relevant for our operations. In addition, we may retain information from closed accounts to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigation, enforce the Crowdtilt Open Terms of Use and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain about you will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use and Checkout Terms. 

## 12\. California Privacy Rights

Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code permits California residents to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information about the types of personal information the business has shared with third parties for those third parties' direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. You may make one request each year by emailing us at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com or writing us at Crowdtilt, Attn: Legal Department, 370 Townsend Street, San Francisco, CA 94107. 

## 13\. Contact Us

Please also feel free to contact us at Privacy@Crowdtilt.com if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy. 

What we feature from Campaigns and Contributors on the Services.
